Ovarro Hanson

Telephone: 07498167172

Email / Website: ovarrohanson@outlook.com, linkedin.com/in/ovarro-hanson, https://github.com/Ohanson18

Professional Summary

Dedicated and versatile professional with over seven years of expertise in combined management and customer service, along with a passion for AWS services. Recently I completed 12 weeks of intense remote training with Generation, on the AWS re/Start programme. Entrepreneurial and hardworking, in 2013 I went into partnership to open an internet café. I successfully managed this for six years, educating myself on software and hardware technologies whilst gaining practical, real-life experience managing tech in a business environment. It is these relevant skills and experiences that prompted me to pursue the AWS programme online, providing an opportunity for me to further develop myself and take on new challenges.

Skill

- Linux
- Python
- Networking
- AWS-Cloud Computing concepts and core services
- Team working

- Time management
- Customer service
- Critical thinking
- Administration and management
- Git/GitHub
- Good interpersonal skills

Experience

AWS re/Start program

- Included: Linux (CLI), Networking, Security, Programming, Databases, Cloud Computing concepts and core services.
- Hands-on experience using AWS services such as: launching EC2, adding security groups, Auto Scaling, troubleshooting VPC, etc.
- Writing Python and Bash Scripts.
- Using Git/GitHub and knowledge of CI/CD.
- Working within various teams, to execute successful presentations.
- Soft skills: self-learning, time management, proactive, problem solving, persistence and teamwork.

General Manager & IT Network Engineer

03/2013 - 11/2019 Young Dreamers Research Centre - Saint Elizabeth, Jamaica

In 2013, my local community of 3,000 people had no internet connection, consequently restricting schooling and local businesses. Through a partnership with someone, we secured funding and created a company to provide internet connectivity. We raised funds, acquired and renovated an old building, and purchased equipment. My role involved; set up and running of daily operations, troubleshooting any issues, including administrative tasks, using QuickBooks and Microsoft Office. I built the IT system including; servers, network, and system configuration. I provided tutorials for members of the community who were inexperienced with technology.

- Increased the demographic from 3000 people to 5000, 90% of the community demands being met and an increase in income by 25% against the expected revenue.
- As the business grew, we sourced sponsorship, that allowed us to assist students with projects, exam preparation and extra learning classes to support their educational development. This resulted in an improvement in 80% of the students' grades as well as gaining the respect and support of established local businesses and international stakeholders.
- Due to demand we implemented an expansion of the services offered by increasing the reach of the
 internet connectivity, the business space, offering utility bill payment services and low-cost overseas
 calls. In this role I learnt how to take personal responsibility, demonstrated persistence, teamwork,
 leadership and adopted the growth mindset.

Property Manager

01/2013 - 11/2019 Bromfield's Property - Saint Elizabeth, Jamaica

The community had a shortage of affordable housing for young people, Bromfield provided 3 flats in two properties. The flats were rented to young people when they moved from home for the first time. My duties included:

- Collect and deposit money into accounts, disburse funds from cash accounts to pay bills or invoices, keep records of collections, disbursements, and ensure accounts were balanced. Function as a liaison between tenants and owners ensuring effective communication, also overseeing repairs and renovations.
- Investigate complaints, disturbances, violations and resolve problems following management rules and
 regulations. This resulted in a, more desirable and comfortable accommodation. I worked to improve
 the longstanding relationship between the property owner, tenants and myself to achieve 100%
 occupancy. This role allowed me to build excellent communication and persuasive skills, along with
 improving my business skills, budgeting and numerical reasoning.

Education and Achievement

09/2020	AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner certification
06/2020	AWS re/Start programme - Generation UK and Ireland
03/2020	Highfield level 2 Award in the Principles of Fire Safety (RQF)
07/2009	Electrical Installation: level 2 - the equivalent to a BTEC Diploma
06/2008	B.B. Coke High School (Equivalent to UK A Levels)
	English (B), Mathematics (E), Social Studies (C)

Interests

- Volunteering and community Involvement: National Youth Council of Jamaica, PRO St. Elizabeth (2018-2019)
- Carpentry
- Music
- Spending time with family and friends